<Document>
# Sentences

  ## Capital
    [bold]Execution[/bold]: Termination of the convict's life.
      - Whenever any execution is performed, outside of Martial Law, a general announcement must be made stating who was executed, and for what reason.
      - The convict may either face execution by firing squad, by lethal electrocution, by being ejected from the station via an airlock (being "spaced"), or by a method of their choosing, at the Judge's sole discretion.
      - If recoverable, their remains must either be cremated, processed via the biomass reclaimer, or stored in the morgue.

    [bold]Exfiltration[/bold]: Immediate retrieval of the convict via a CentComm or GALPOL prison transport.
      - The prisoner may be held within the permanent brig until the transport arrives.

    [bold]Extended Confinement[/bold]: The convict has the same rights as any other prisoner within the Permanent Brig, whether they arrived by transport or were sentenced to Extended Confinement.
    - The prisoner may be held within the permanent brig until the transport arrives.

  ## Standard
    [bold]Brigging[/bold]: Placing the convict into a temporary holding cell.

    [bold]Catch & Release[/bold]: Taking the convict to Security, processing them, searching them, and then releasing them.

    [bold]Demotion[/bold]:  Downgrading the convict’s employment contract and revoking their access accordingly, with permission from or when ordered by the convict’s head of department. May be applied when the convict has committed a crime relating to their employment within their department or with NanoTrasen as a whole.

    [bold]Licence restriction[/bold]: Downgrading or suspending the convict’s armament licence and confiscating possessions accordingly. May be applied when the convict is guilty of possession or a crime involving a weapon they were lawfully permitted to carry.

    [bold]Licence restriction[/bold]:  Removal of the convict’s noöspheric or other otherworldy connections by use of mindbreaker toxin, ardent censer, or any other means. May be applied when the convict is guilty of a crime in which they use psionics, otherworldy abilities, or similar powers.
</Document>
