<Document>
  # Rule C3: Antagonism
By picking an antagonist role you are accepting that you will be expected to be a driving force in the round’s narrative . This means that you should generally try to stick to the expectations of your antagonist role. Deviations are allowed with sufficient roleplay and in-character justification, especially when done to make your impact and role more interesting to the greater narrative.


Players are free to ahelp and request other players to receive an antagonist status when they have rolled an antagonist role by accident.


Given objectives are never mandatory to follow, and act as more of a general suggestion and guideline to your role. Players have the freedom to come up with, and modify their own objectives. Modified or replaced objectives must:


-Follow proper escalation (Review B1.4).


-Be within what would reasonably be expected of your role.


-Aim to create an interesting story, and engage with the crew.


-Be sufficiently backed by roleplay justification.


 ## Rule C3.1: Team antagonists

When playing a team antagonist you must assist your team if possible through gameplay, roleplay, or other methods. Completely disengaging from the team antagonist on both a gameplay and roleplay level is prohibited. Leaving the game via cryosleep or disconnecting is explicitly allowed, as long as an attempt to reduce the negative impact on your team is made, such as handing over important gear, ahelping, etc.

 ## Rule C3.2: End of round griefing

 Antagonists should avoid completeting objectives on the evacuation shuttle or at midpoint.

 [color=#ff0000]Antagonists are explicitly prohibited from causing damage to the evacuation shuttle or midpoint.[/color] Unless: they are a round ending antagonist, and doing so would contribute to their objectives.

 Examples of justified EORG could be but are not limited to: nukies retrieving the disk from a docked or departing evac, dragons storming evac to collect bodies, and xenoborgs collecting brains from crew attempting to leave via evac.
</Document>
